Hello Ajay,
Hello friends,
I am Sumit Bhandariya from Health Insurance, this is Doctor, I welcome you.
Thank you very much
for watching this video. Today our topic is Health
Insurance Portability. So,
see what is portability.
Today I have a mobile phone SIM of a private company for a school
and I have been using it for
years. So if I want to
support this service provider, if
someone wants to switch from Airtel to Idea, if he
wants to switch from Jio to Idea, then he can change his phone
number without changing to another company. If
you are buying your product, the number will remain your SIM. So, this is
called portability. There is
a provision in such health insurance
that if you are having
problems with your agent, or you
feel that something from one company is not right, or
you are getting a better product from another company, or
you have started a new job, he
approached them saying that you should
leave the original company and come to him. So,
when you switch from one company to another,
this is called health
insurance portability.
Now, there are two types of portability.
One is that  If you go from one company to another, then it is
called
portability from one company to another.
Portability is done by Indrasen
company. You have a company that has revised one of its
products, so you have a constipation option in
another product within the same company.
You can
also do positivity in Planets Airplane, which will be less than the insurance company, within the
same company.
Only the product is changing.
Now both these things are simple,
but the important point in this is that
which mistake should we avoid.
Whenever you are going from one company to another, you have to
fill a form in the other company. You will have to give your old
policy details to the link office and when
you took the policy for the first time and now when you are
going to another company in 2021
for portability, therefore, it is compulsory to
tell about any change in your medical history. If
you are going to another company, then
according to the ID, what will they co
-own for you, which condition of your old policy has been
transferred to them here under portability.  It will be
thought that your policy of 10 lakhs was running for many years, for
3 years, so if there is a
stain in this company in another company, then the
10 lakhs there will be considered 3 years old and 14 years will
start, so what did the
meaning of year old on that day, that
whatever you can put on its meeting, then
here also it will be considered 3 years, when you
come to another company, then the
terms and conditions of this company are its features,
bonus and you have to select,
now this number portability, then
four things can be
made different options in it, one spray polythene of 10 lakhs,
from 10 lakhs to 10 lakhs further, second you had
reached the old company of 10 lakhs, now
here your 15, 20 lakhs good, that is,
increasing is included, every third you had a
different combination in the policy there and
here in the policy there is a can you babu for school, so the
demographics of the child will change in the policy, there will be audition of a family member,
fourth it is possible that you
can also reduce your SA mix  Their income had crossed Rs 10 lakhs
for pension, if you are thinking of
going to another company to save money, then
first of all this Rs 5 lakh will be
transferred to Someshwar, these are
technical things, what do you get,
now when you are going from one company to another,
what things should be kept in mind,
what mistakes should be avoided, first of all, whenever you are going to
another company, try to
fill the proposal form of the other company in the possibilities form with one hand only, what is the advantage of hand-made form, that
you get to know that the
other company has asked me questions in this proposal form,
if any of your
service provider, your agent or
intermediate or someone online helps you in getting these questions done,
if they say
that sir, no problem, pay the payment by link,
just take the documents, we will do your tax,
then do not enter, the only thing that saves you on the legal level
here is that
you read the proposal form and
declared everything honestly,
when you are doing the possibilities here,
You should never overdo this process, always
fill the proposal form manually.
Second thing, if you have been with the company for
more than a year, then try
not to do portability within another company. It is
possible to do it only
if there are unavoidable circumstances, if there is an emergency, if something happens
where it would be called an
emergency situation, that it is
beyond our control, that we cannot handle it now, only then it is
necessary to do it in another company, that is, what
I basically mean to say is, try
not to do portability, see,
play these points, when you have been with the same company for
many years, there is loyalty, then there is
support from the company also for
many years, so it is
better to be at peace there. Third thing, if you have a
difference of just ₹1000-₹3000 in the premium, that is,
you are saving money, then do
not do portability at all. The magnitude, that is, the
magnitude of the benefits you are getting, should be at least  It should be 50%, either
you are getting 50% more cover for the same money
or you get
50% in the next company
or you are getting some feature
which you think, yes I wanted this, it was not like that it should be
in my device, it should be in my phone, so
you have to make a judgment, it was
not like this feature which you like very much, go ahead and try it, whether it will
help you or
not, only time will tell, but don't
pimp it at all, don't go backwards and
move from one company to another, then
what happens in most of the cases is that when you
sit in the same company for many years, that is the
best possible place for you,
stay where you are sitting, that is
good for you, so try, if you
get a lot of advantage, that is fine, even then
you should switch from one company to another,
fourth thing is also to take a policy, so try to check
your policy within 13 years and
within that, if you need to sit here
in the other company, then a proper
subscribe to your channel  You don't have to do
this company and subscribe to this
effort by taking it from someone there,
sitting with someone there, you have a home, so
if you take care of these things, then
you will do one thing, whenever you will ask a question, from
here you are a Sikarwar, from there
you will get a reply, will
it be very positive or at least negative, a
positive reply means you
asked to fill the form, then the other person says everything is
absolutely fine, we will
take the policy by filling the home, for you my health
history, do you have to use this card, do
not use it, if the other person says use it, do
not take the policy without it, then
do this subject that you are getting into
good hands at one place, you are going to join a profession,
what if negative,
you said that I have to get the proposal form, then
that evening he asked you to get the policy,
no sir, you have stopped calling me on the phone
or the other person says sir, it's okay,
trust me, just
sign here, I will fill the form or the
other person is asking the question  Is it or not, sir, there is no
logic behind it. If you do
n't need it, please stay away from such a place. If
you want to judge, use some top
questions. You will
get a little clarity from the person in front of you. Last week,
any question related to it was completely from the
center. It is a consultant or an
urgent, a broker or an online
website. Everyone has to run their household, some
job, they also have to work to earn money. So
you should not get into the commercial angle of that thing.
You should basically focus on where
I have to move from here to another place. So
this process has to be done correctly.
I always keep one thing in mind, if you do
not have the proposal form that you have declared under the old policy, then
assume that now those who are
going for portability to another company, there is a
lot of scope for mistake. That is why
IATA has qualified its process. The
more you follow it, the more it will be
in your benefit. That is, do
not work in too much firefighting mode. Take it
easy.  Keep one thing in
mind if your age is above 45 years or if
possible then always take such a policy from
such a company if you are
forced to do portability and you are not able to do it then
never take medical checkup photos,
these policies are
for those who are above 45 to 50 years of age,
try these, if you are fifty plus or
six plus then it is impossible, you will
not want to take this policy, they will give you a
portability policy, so
take it right now without medical, if you are a doctor they
themselves send you an email saying that my
body is absolutely fine, I
guarantee you can take it, so do whatever you
want, if you ask the other company to get
my medical checkup done without
medical checkup, what happens in getting my medical checkup done
that you are scared, I am a doctor, then
tomorrow if there is even a slight mistake in the office, you were
working in your old company for 10
years, if you come to another company after six months, if you
ask for it, the company
presses you with a question and you do not have an
answer for it  No, this has not been disclosed to you,
all the benefits of immediate portability will be lost, the
policy can also be cancelled,
why should I write this and mostly it happens that
those who can avail the portability, the
next company will give them this because they
too have the liability of portability, so
their lips are looked at very closely,
especially they can see it from the roar, high clean,
investigation
etc. also keeps happening, so try, if it is
your duty, it is to
fill the form properly, delete all the things properly
and if possible, then prostate, give
them courage, many times
a person already has a clean form for this poll
and this is a 10 year, 15 year old car,
if your car is giving good benefits,
your TV is giving benefits, your 5 year
old mobile is late, then why not spoil the
good thing also in the name of this feature,
okay, so what happens many times is that
God bless the system, where we are sitting,
it has placed us here  It
happens many times with Vastu Shastra, if it is
very good that if your work
system is running very well, many times what
happens is that
according to this, you should fold it where
you are sitting on the order petition,
do portability but try to
find your professional, yes if any person
wants to get a new policy under health insurance portability or someone needs to renew his Gyan Singh policy, or you
want to plan a policy for your parents, they have an
old policy running, you
want to get a policy along with this, you are
working in a company, how do you have to plan the policy with this, if
you have any such suggestion,
you can take help consultancy from us, that
thing which is feedback, there is a video above, if you
click on that link, then you will get clarity about our health
insurance consultancy offering
and my
request here is that if you are getting
involved in job consultancy, then watch this video
on 1234 repeatedly,
answers to all the questions are already given in it,
which you  If you need any additional information,
you can email us at
healthinsurance.sahi.com
or infoairteldishsansad.com or
mail on any ID, our team will
reply to you and thank you
very much for taking out time to watch this video.
If you like this channel, if its subscribers
increase a little,
we will also like to do some
good work. Like the video and
subscribe to the channel. If you have any suggestion of any kind, please
send it to us by mail or
WhatsApp on this number. We will try to
answer your question or will
try our best to fulfill whatever suggestion you have. So,
thank you very much
for watching this video. Thank you very much,
I am Jain
[Music]